<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shivansh Subramanian</title>
    <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shivansh Subramanian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 15:08:33 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code: 2022</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 15:08:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This blog is about my contributions to sktime during GSoC &amp;lsquo;22.
Introduction sktime is a library based on sklearn meant for time-series data and problems. It has easy to use implementations of important statistical and ML-based estimators for the purposes of classification, regression and forecasting. This summer, I joined the sktime time on the project to add DL estimators to sktime.
The main motivation for adding DL models in sktime is the recent surge in using DL networks in time series related computational problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psuedo Random Functions</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/prf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 08:42:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/prf/</guid>
      <description>A simple explanation on what Psuedo Random numbers are, and how we can securely send information using PRF.
Introduction In a lot of computational and mathematical programs, random numbers are important. Might be just to take probability, to shuffle a deck of cards or to simulate a game. The only way to get a number which is truly random is to depend on certain physical phenomenon which is unpredictable, like radioactive decay of isotopes or airwave static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast Multiplication</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/fastmult/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 21:32:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/fastmult/</guid>
      <description>Multiplication, generally, is relatively easy to do, understand and code. Even the 2nd standard algorithm of multiple each digit with every other digit is simple enough to write. The issue is that such an algorithm takes $O(n^2)$,time complexity, which is a lot, especially if you want to multiply huge numbers. Hence why you need better algorithms in place to do your job. Note, languages like Python have lots of optimisations on top of specific algorithms used for computing products when the user types in a simple &amp;lsquo;*&amp;rsquo;, but the article is more about understanding these algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up your PopOS</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/popos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 21:18:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/popos/</guid>
      <description>So I used to love ElementaryOS (still do :p) even as a programmer, since its UI was intuitive and clean, and nothing else needed to be done on top of it. During one of my assignments though, I realised the issue I was having was my OS was in Ubuntu 18.04 instead of 20.04, which was a problem. Simple enough, I tried to update it as I had tried to update by Ubuntu (you could do that simply by a command on terminal).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced Row Echelon Form</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/rref/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 21:13:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/rref/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The blog explains how to find reduced row-echelon form of a matrix in python&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Classifier</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 21:15:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/classifier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The blog explains how to create a linear classifier from scratch using MSE loss and Sigmoid Function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reversing Huge Files</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/huge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 21:16:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/huge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog contains an explanation and tutorial of how to reverse very large files in C&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-Occurance Matrix</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/cooc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 21:12:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/cooc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog contains an explanation and tutorial to create word embeddings via co-occurance matrix and svd&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OWASP Top 10</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/owasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 21:08:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/owasp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog contains my walkthrough of the OWASP room in tryhackme while trying to learn more about cyber security. Check out the original room as well &lt;a href=&#34;https://tryhackme.com/room/owasptop10&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networks</title>
      <link>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 17:58:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aurumnpegasus.github.io/posts/networks/</guid>
      <description>Here is the stuff I read related to networks, different models and their working,
OSI Model The OSI Model (Open Systems Interconnection Model) is a conceptual framework used to describe the functions of a networking system. It defines rules and requirements that support effortless data transfer between different products and software. In the OSI reference model, the communications between a computing system are split into seven different abstraction layers: Physical, Data Link, Network, Transport, Session, Presentation, and Application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
